A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, projects, SG 1.1, Series 300 Latin America - Series 833 Lebanon FA386b
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Mexico, 1913-1969; 323; 10.4 Cubic Feet; 26 __Boxes __10.4 cubic feet
  - Agriculture - Scholarships - (Mauricio Munoz, Jose - Navarez Morales, Ignacio), 1947-1952 (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Agriculture - Scholarships - (Ortega Corona, Alejandro - Pacheco Mendivil, Francisco), 1948-1950, 1952-1954 (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Agriculture - Scholarships - (Palacios Aviles, Raul - Ramirez Genel, Marcos), 1947-1952 (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Agriculture - Scholarships - (Rodriguez, Antonio - Rosado Espinosa, Humberto), 1948-1954 (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - Agriculture - Scholarships - (Sanchez Duron, Nicolas - Santamaria, Rodolfo), 1946-1950, 1952-1955 (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Agriculture - Scholarships - (Servin Sevilla, Leopoldo Francisco - Terrazas Loyola, Jose), 1946-1949, 1954-1956 (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Agriculture - Scientific Advisors, 1942-1952 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Agriculture - Scientific Advisors, 1942-1952 (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - Agriculture - Scientific Advisors, 1942-1952 (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - Agriculture - Scientific Advisors, 1942-1952 (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Agriculture - Scientific Advisors, 1942-1952 (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Agriculture - Scientific Advisors, 1942-1952 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - Agriculture - Scientific Advisors, 1942-1952 (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - Agriculture - Scientific Advisors, 1953-1955 (Box 10, Folder 64)
  - Agriculture - Scientific Advisors, 1953-1955 (Box 10, Folder 65)
  - Agriculture - Scientific Advisors, 1953-1955 (Box 10, Folder 66)
  - Agriculture - Scientific Advisors - "Minutes of Agricultural Advisory Committee Meetings" - AGR SA-1, 1942-1955 (Box 10, Folder 67)
  - Agriculture - Scientific Advisors - "Minutes of Agricultural Advisory Committee Meetings" - AGR SA-1, 1942-1955 (Box 10, Folder 68)
  - Agriculture - Scientific Advisors - Report - "Annual Meeting Board of Agricultural Consultants" - AGR SA-2, 1953; 1 item (Box 11, Folder 69)
  - Agriculture - Survey Commission, 1941 (Box 11, Folder 70)
  - Agriculture - Survey Commission, 1941 (Box 11, Folder 71)
  - Agriculture - Survey Commission, 1941 (Box 11, Folder 72)
  - Agriculture - Temporary Aides, 1947, 1950-1956 (Box 11, Folder 73)
  - Agriculture - Temporary Aides - Bradfield, Richard, 1953-1954 (Box 11, Folder 74)
  - Agriculture - Young, E.C. - (Board of Consultants, Travel Grant), 1953-1954 (Box 11, Folder 75)
  - American School Foundation - Building Fund, 1950, 1953-1954 (Box 11, Folder 76)
  - Hospital de Enfermedades de la Nutricion, Mexico City - (Laguna, Jose; Equipment), 1951-1952 (Box 11, Folder 77)
  - Institute of Tropical Diseases - Insectary - (Equipment), 1948-1950 (Box 12, Folder 78)
  - Nutrition, 1941-1949 (Box 12, Folder 79)
  - Nutrition, 1941-1949 (Box 12, Folder 80)
  - Nutrition, 1941-1949 (Box 12, Folder 81)
  - Nutrition, 1941-1949 (Box 12, Folder 82)
  - Nutrition, 1941-1949 (Box 12, Folder 83)
  - State of Mexico - Agriculture - Personnel - (Moore, Wilbert E.), 1951-1952 (Box 12, Folder 84)
  - State of Mexico - Agriculture - Staff - (DeGraff, Herrell F.), 1952 (Box 12, Folder 85)
  - Typhus Fever, 1933-1934, 1940, 1942-June 1943 (Box 12, Folder 86)
  - Typhus Fever, 1933-1934, 1940, 1942-June 1943 (Box 12, Folder 87)
  - Typhus Fever, 1933-1934, 1940, 1942-June 1943 (Box 12, Folder 88)
  - Typhus Fever, July 1943-1947 (Box 13, Folder 89)
  - Typhus Fever, July 1943-1947 (Box 13, Folder 90)
  - Typhus Fever, July 1943-1947 (Box 13, Folder 91)
  - Typhus Fever - Reports, 1943-1944; 2 items (Box 13, Folder 92)
  - Mexico - Medical Sciences, 323.A
    - (Medical Sciences), 1920, 1922, 1925, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 93)
    - (Medical Sciences), 1920, 1922, 1925, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 94)
    - LAM Lambert, Robert A. and Gregg, Alan "Medical Education in Mexico"(, 1923, 1936-1941 (Box 13, Folder 95)
    - National Institute of Cardiology, Mexico City - Equipment, 1941-1942, 1944-1952 (Box 13, Folder 96)
    - National Institute of Cardiology, Mexico City - Equipment, 1941-1942, 1944-1952 (Box 13, Folder 97)
    - National Institute of Cardiology, Mexico City - Equipment, 1941-1942, 1944-1952 (Box 13, Folder 98)
    - National Institute of Cardiology, Mexico City - Equipment, 1941-1942, 1944-1952 (Box 13, Folder 99)
    - National Institute of Cardiology, Mexico City - Equipment, 1953-1955, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 100)
    - National Institute of Cardiology, Mexico City - Equipment - Report, 1954; 1 item (Box 14, Folder 101)
    - National Institute of Cardiology, Mexico City - Pharmacology - (Mendez, Rafael; Travel Grant), 1950 (Box 14, Folder 102)
    - National Polytechnic Institute, Mexico City - del Pozo, Efren C. - (Physiology), 1942-1944 (Box 14, Folder 103)
    - University of Chihuahua - Ornelas K., Julio - (Medicine, Travel Grant), 1955 (Box 14, Folder 104)
    - University of Guanajuato - Gomez Guerra, Francisco - (Thoracic Surgery, Travel Grant), 1953-1954 (Box 14, Folder 105)
    - University of Guanajuato - Gueda, Juan Arturo - (Medical Education, Travel Grant), 1955 (Box 14, Folder 106)
    - University of Mexico - Guevara-Rojas, Albert - (Physilogy, Equipment and Supplies), 1942-1948 (Box 14, Folder 107)
    - University of Mexico - Laguna, Jose - (Medical Education, Travel Grant), 1953-1954 (Box 14, Folder 108)
    - University of Mexico - Physiology - (Equipment), 1940-1944, 1946-1948. 1950-1952 (Box 14, Folder 109)
    - University of Mexico - Physiology - (Equipment), 1940-1944, 1946-1948. 1950-1952 (Box 14, Folder 110)
    - University of Mexico - Physiology - del Pozo, Elfren C. - (Equipment), 1949-1952 (Box 14, Folder 111)
  - Mexico - Natural Sciences and Agriculture, 323.D
    - Agricultural Exchange - (A-Z), 1952-1954, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 112)
    - Escuela Superior de Agricultura "Antonio Narro", Saltillo, 1947-1951 (Box 14, Folder 113)
    - Escuela Superior de Agricultura "Antonio Narro", Saltillo - Martinez Medina, Lorenzo - (Travel Grant), 1953-1954 (Box 15, Folder 114)
    - Instituto Percuario - Tellez Giron, Alfredo - (Animal Pathology, Travel Grant), 1943-1946 (Box 15, Folder 115)
    - Instituto Technologico de Monterrey - Agronomy - (Equipment and Supplies), 1949 (Box 15, Folder 116)
    - Instituto Technologico de Monterrey - Mathematics - (Equipment), 1947-1949 (Box 15, Folder 117)
    - Mathematics - (Mathematical Congress of Mexican Mathematicians, Travel Grants), 1945 (Box 15, Folder 118)
    - Morales, Maximo E. - (National College of Agriculture, Chapingo) - (Chemistry, Travel Grant), 1946-1947 (Box 15, Folder 119)
    - National Polytechnic Institute - Biological Library, 1946-1947 (Box 15, Folder 120)
    - National School of Agriculture, Chapingo - (Entomology, Plant Pathology, Library), 1946-1950, 1968-1969 (Box 15, Folder 121)
    - National School of Agriculture, Chapingo - (Entomology, Plant Pathology, Library), 1946-1950, 1968-1969 (Box 15, Folder 0121A)
    - Palacios, Raul - (Agricultural Research Centers, Travel Grant), 1954 (Box 15, Folder 122)
    - Secretaria de Marina - Rural Fish Culture, 1949-1953 (Box 15, Folder 123)
    - Secretaria de Marina - Rural Fish Culture, 1949-1953 (Box 15, Folder 124)
    - Secretaria de Marina - Rural Fish Culture - Reports, 1951-1952; 20 items (Box 15, Folder 125)
    - University of Mexico - Chemistry, 1941-1955 (Box 16, Folder 126)
    - University of Mexico - Chemistry, 1941-1955 (Box 16, Folder 127)
    - University of Mexico - Chemistry, 1941-1955 (Box 16, Folder 128)
    - University of Mexico - Chemistry, 1941-1955 (Box 16, Folder 129)
    - University of Mexico - Chemistry, 1941-1955 (Box 16, Folder 130)
    - University of Mexico - Chemistry, 1941-1955 (Box 16, Folder 131)
    - University of Mexico - Chemistry, 1941-1955 (Box 16, Folder 132)
    - University of Mexico - Chemistry, 1956-1958 (Box 17, Folder 133)
    - University of Mexico - Mathematics, 1952-1954 (Box 17, Folder 134)
    - University of Mexico - Physics - (Banos, Alfredo), 1941-1945 (Box 17, Folder 135)
    - University of Mexico - Physics - (Banos, Alfredo), 1941-1945 (Box 17, Folder 136)
    - University of Mexico - Vasquez G., Leonila - (Entomology, Travel Grant), 1954-1955 (Box 17, Folder 137)
    - Villalobos, F., Alejandro - (Inverterate Biology, Travel Grant), 1954-1955 (Box 17, Folder 138)
  - Mexico - Hookworm, 323.H
    - (Hookworm), 1924, 1928-1930, 1933, 1945-1946 (Box 17, Folder 139)
    - (Hookworm), 1924, 1928-1930, 1933, 1945-1946 (Box 17, Folder 140)
    - (Hookworm), 1924, 1928-1930, 1933, 1945-1946 (Box 17, Folder 141)
    - (Hookworm), 1924, 1928-1930, 1933, 1945-1946 (Box 17, Folder 142)
  - Mexico - Malaria, 323.I
    - (Malaria) - Appropriations, 1936-1952 (Box 17, Folder 143)
    - (Malaria) - Appropriations, 1936-1952 (Box 17, Folder 144)
    - (Malaria), 1935-1950 (Box 18, Folder 145)
    - (Malaria), 1935-1950 (Box 18, Folder 146)
    - (Malaria), 1935-1950 (Box 18, Folder 147)
    - (Malaria), 1935-1950 (Box 18, Folder 148)
    - (Malaria), 1935-1950 (Box 18, Folder 149)
    - (Malaria), 1935-1950 (Box 18, Folder 150)
    - (Malaria), 1935-1950 (Box 18, Folder 151)
    - (Malaria), 1935-1950 (Box 18, Folder 152)
    - (Malaria), 1951-1952 (Box 19, Folder 153)
  - Mexico - Public Health Demonstrations, 323.J
    - (Public Health Demonstrations) - (Appropriations), 1930-1940, 1942-1950 (Box 19, Folder 154)
    - (Public Health Demonstrations) - (Appropriations), 1930-1940, 1942-1950 (Box 19, Folder 155)
    - (Public Health Demonstrations), 1928-May 1935 (Box 19, Folder 156)
    - (Public Health Demonstrations), 1928-May 1935 (Box 19, Folder 157)
    - (Public Health Demonstrations), 1928-May 1935 (Box 19, Folder 158)
    - (Public Health Demonstrations), 1928-May 1935 (Box 19, Folder 159)
    - (Public Health Demonstrations), 1928-May 1935 (Box 19, Folder 160)
    - (Public Health Demonstrations), June 1935-1947 (Box 20, Folder 161)
    - (Public Health Demonstrations), June 1935-1947 (Box 20, Folder 162)
    - (Public Health Demonstrations), June 1935-1947 (Box 20, Folder 163)
    - (Public Health Demonstrations), June 1935-1947 (Box 20, Folder 164)
    - (Public Health Demonstrations), June 1935-1947 (Box 20, Folder 165)
    - (Public Health Demonstrations), June 1935-1947 (Box 20, Folder 166)
    - (Public Health Demonstrations), June 1935-1947 (Box 20, Folder 167)
    - (Public Health Demonstrations), 1948-1952 (Box 21, Folder 168)
    - (Public Health Demonstrations) - Minatitlan - Puerto Mexico, 1928-1932 (Box 21, Folder 169)
    - (Public Health Demonstrations) - Vera Cruz, 1928-1937 (Box 21, Folder 170)
    - (Public Health Demonstrations) - Vera Cruz, 1928-1937 (Box 21, Folder 171)
  - Mexico - Epidemiological Investigations and Studies, 323.Q
    - (Epidemiological Investigations and Studies), 1923, 1930-1937 (Box 21, Folder 172)
    - (Epidemiological Investigations and Studies), 1923, 1930-1937 (Box 21, Folder 173)
    - (Epidemiological Investigations and Studies) - Reports, 1931-1932, 1934-1935; 3 items (Box 21, Folder 174)
  - Mexico - Humanities and Arts, 323.R
    - Benjamin Franklin Library, Mexico City - Microfilming, 1941-1948, 1952 (Box 21, Folder 175)
    - Benjamin Franklin Library, Mexico City - Microfilming, 1941-1948, 1952 (Box 21, Folder 176)
    - Colegio de Mexico, Mexico City, 1940-1952 (Box 22, Folder 177)
    - Colegio de Mexico, Mexico City, 1940-1952 (Box 22, Folder 178)
    - Colegio de Mexico, Mexico City, 1940-1952 (Box 22, Folder 179)
    - Colegio de Mexico, Mexico City, 1940-1952 (Box 22, Folder 180)
    - Colegio de Mexico, Mexico City - History, 1945-1946, 1948 (Box 22, Folder 181)
    - Colegio de Mexico, Mexico City - Music - Pope, Isabel - (Travel Grant), 1949-1950 (Box 22, Folder 182)
    - Colegio de Mexico, Mexico City - Music - (Salzar, Adolfo; Travel Grant), 1949, 1954 (Box 22, Folder 183)
    - Colegio de Mexico, Mexico City - Zavala, Silvio - (History), 1943-1948 (Box 22, Folder 184)
    - Guadalajara Library - (Jalisco State Library), 1939-1941 (Box 22, Folder 185)
    - Guadalajara Library - (Jalisco State Library), 1942-1945, 1948 (Box 23, Folder 186)
    - Guadalajara Library - (Jalisco State Library) - Tello's Chronicle, 1941 (Box 23, Folder 187)
    - Library Reorganization - (National Library of Mexico), 1940, 1947-1948, 1951-1957 (Box 23, Folder 188)
    - Library Reorganization - (National Library of Mexico), 1940, 1947-1948, 1951-1957 (Box 23, Folder 189)
    - Library Reorganization - (National Library of Mexico), 1940, 1947-1948, 1951-1957 (Box 23, Folder 190)
    - National Institute of Anthropology and History, 1939-1943 (Box 23, Folder 191)
    - National Institute of Anthropology and History, 1939-1943 (Box 23, Folder 192)
    - National Institute of Anthropology and History, 1939-1943 (Box 23, Folder 193)
    - National Institute of Anthropology and History, 1939-1943 (Box 23, Folder 194)
    - National Institute of Anthropology and History, 1939-1943 (Box 23, Folder 195)
    - National Institute of Anthropology and History, 1944-1955 (Box 24, Folder 196)
    - National Institute of Anthropology and History, 1944-1955 (Box 24, Folder 197)
    - National Institute of Anthropology and History, 1944-1955 (Box 24, Folder 198)
    - National Institute of Anthropology and History, 1944-1955 (Box 24, Folder 199)
    - National Institute of Anthropology and History, 1944-1955 (Box 24, Folder 200)
    - National Institute of Anthropology and History - (Annual Report), 1945 (Box 24, Folder 201)
    - National Institute of Anthropology and History - (Carrasco Pizana, Pedro; Thesis), 1945 (Box 24, Folder 202)
    - National Institute of Anthropology and History - Central American Survey - (Rubin, Daniel F.), 1940-1942 (Box 24, Folder 203)
    - National Institute of Anthropology and History - Central American Survey - (Rubin, Daniel F.) - Report, 1940; 1 item (Box 25, Folder 204)
    - National Institute of Anthropology and History - Guzman, Eulalia - (Archives, Library), 1940-1941, 1943 (Box 25, Folder 205)
    - National Institute of Anthropology and History - Guzman, Eulalia - (Archives, Library), 1940-1941, 1943 (Box 25, Folder 206)
    - National Institute of Anthropology and History - Microfilm Center, 1948-1952 (Box 25, Folder 207)
    - National Institute of Anthropology and History - Museum Survey - (Solorzano, Carlos), 1948-1950, 1952 (Box 25, Folder 208)
    - National Institute of Anthropology and History - Tax, Sol, 1942-1944 (Box 25, Folder 209)
    - Otero, Clementina - (Yale University Drama Department, Children's Theatre), 1941-1945 (Box 25, Folder 210)
    - Otero, Clementina - (Yale University Drama Department, Children's Theatre), 1941-1945 (Box 25, Folder 211)
    - Union Library Catalog, Mexico City - (American Library Association), 1941-1950 (Box 25, Folder 212)
    - Union Library Catalog, Mexico City - (American Library Association), 1941-1950 (Box 25, Folder 213)
    - Union Library Catalog, Mexico City - (American Library Association), 1941-1950 (Box 25, Folder 214)
    - University of Mexico - Philosophy, 1943-1949, 1954 (Box 26, Folder 215)
    - University of Mexico - Philosophy, 1943-1949, 1954 (Box 26, Folder 216)
    - University of Mexico - Philosophy, 1943-1949, 1954 (Box 26, Folder 217)
    - Usigli, Rodolfo - (Translation and Publication of English and Spanish Materials), 1940-1942 (Box 26, Folder 218)
    - Usigli, Rodolfo - (Translation and Publication of English and Spanish Materials), 1940-1942 (Box 26, Folder 219)
    - Yucatan Linguistic Studies - (Morley, Sylvanus G.), 1942-1944, 1948 (Box 26, Folder 220)
  - Mexico - Social Sciences, 323.S
    - Mexican Social Science Research Center, 1928-1931, 1933 (Box 26, Folder 221)
    - Mexican Social Science Research Center - Reports, 1928-1929, 1931-1932; 5 items (Box 26, Folder 222)
    - National Polytechnic Institute - Indianists Conference, 1939-1940 (Box 26, Folder 223)
    - Zubiran, Salvadore - (Visit, Child Welfare), 1937-1939 (Box 26, Folder 224)
- Nicaragua, 1922-1939; 325; 0.2 Cubic Feet; 1 __Box __0.2 cubic feet
  Aside from a report on medical education in Nicaragua, which was part of a world-wide Rockefeller Foundation survey of medical education in the early 1920's, the files are mainly concerned with public health, including malaria control and health demonstration and laboratory units.
  325 A Medical sciences (research conducted in medical schools or medical research institutes, research directly applicable to the mental and physical health of human beings)
  325 I Malaria
  325 J Public health demonstrations, local health units
  325 K Health services (epidemiology, reform, public health administartion, laboratories, vital statistics, and particularly sanitary engineering)
  - Nicaragua - Medical Sciences, 325.A
    - LAM Lambert, Robert A. "Medical Education in Nicaragua", 1922 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Nicaragua - Malaria, 325.I
    - Managua Malaria Control, 1931-1933 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Rivas - La Puebla - Malaria Control, 1933-1937 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Nicaragua - Public Health Demonstrations, 325.J
    - Chinandega Health Unit, 1933-1937 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Managua Health Unit, 1937-1939 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Rivas Health Unit, 1934-1938 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Nicaragua - Health Services, 325.K
    - Public Health Laboratory Service, 1928, 1930-1938 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Panama, 1930-1948; 327; 0.8 Cubic Feet; 2 __Boxes __0.8 cubic feet
  Most of the records in this series relate to health projection in Panama. Files concerning public health matters document grants for malaria studies, health demonstration and laboratories, and work on yellow fever and tuberculosis. There is also a file relating to Foundation support of a nursing school at the Santo Tomas Hospital, 1933-1945.
  327 C Nursing (nursing education, public health nursing)
  327 I Malaria
  327 J Public health demonstrations, local health units
  327 K Health services (epidemiology, reform, public health administartion, laboratories, vital statistics, and particularly sanitary engineering)
  327 O Yellow fever
  327 T Tuberculosis
  - Panama - Nursing, 327.C
    - Santo Tomas Hospital - Nursing School, 1933-1945 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Santo Tomas Hospital - Nursing School, 1933-1945 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Santo Tomas Hospital - Nursing School, 1933-1945 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Santo Tomas Hospital - Nursing School, 1933-1945 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Panama - Malaria, 327.I
    - Bocas del Toro Islands - (Malaria Studies), 1931-1934 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Panama - Public Health Demonstrations, 327.J
    - (Public Health Demonstrations), 1930-1940 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - (Public Health Demonstrations), 1930-1940 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - (Public Health Demonstrations), 1930-1940 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - (Public Health Demonstrations) - Report, 1936; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Panama - Health Services, 327.K
    - Public Health Laboratory, 1936-1938 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Panama - Yellow Fever, 327.O
    - (Yellow Fever), 1936-1948 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - (Yellow Fever), 1936-1948 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Panama - Tuberculosis, 327.T
    - (Tuberculosis), 1930-1936, 1940-1942 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - (Tuberculosis), 1930-1936, 1940-1942 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - (Tuberculosis), 1930-1936, 1940-1942 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Paraguay, 1919-1942; 329; 0.2 Cubic Feet; 1 __Box __0.2 cubic feet
  These records relate primarily to public health programs. The earliest files concern the medical sciences and include a report on medical education and public health in Paraguay. Later files (1924-1942) have to do with Foundation activity in the control of hookworm and yellow fever.
  329 (no program letter, general material which does not fit into a particular program area)
  329 A Medical sciences (research conducted in medical schools or medical research institutes, research directly applicable to the mental and physical health of human beings)
  329 H Hookworm
  329 O Yellow fever
  - Contracts, 1932, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Paraguay - Medical Sciences, 329.A
    - (Medical Sciences), 1926 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - PEA-1 Pearce, Lambert, Hackett, Strode "Medical Education and Public Health in Paraguay", 1919-1925 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Paraguay - Hookworm, 329.H
    - (Hookworm), 1925, 1927-1929 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Paraguay - Yellow Fever, 329.O
    - (Yellow Fever), 1932-1935, 1937-1939, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Peru, 1919-1958; 331; 2.4 Cubic Feet; 6 __Boxes __2.4 cubic feet
  The earliest files, dealing with medical sciences, include a report (1926) which resulted from The Rockefeller Foundation's world-wide survey of medical education. Some public health material is present, including files relating to the ICA Health Service, the National Institute of Hygiene, malaria and yellow fever. The Foundation made grants in the medical sciences during the 1940's and 1950's to the University of San Marcos in Lima; it also supported agricultural and veterinary research in the 1950's at various institutions including the National School of Agriculture in La Molina and the University of San Marcos at Lima.
  331 (no program letter, general material which does not fit into a particular program area)
  331 A Medical sciences (research conducted in medical schools or medical research institutes, research directly applicable to the mental and physical health of human beings)
  331 D Natural sciences and agriculture (research usually conducted in departments outside of medical schools, research in pure science, veterinary medicine or agriculture)
  331 I Malaria
  331 J Public health demonstrations, local health units
  331 K Health Services (epidemiology, reform, public health administration, laboratories, vital statistics, and particularly sanitary engineering)
  331 O Yellow fever
  331 R Humanities and arts
  331 S Social sciences
  - Health - Lynch C., Alfredo - (Travel Grant), 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Health - Personnel - (Ministry of Health), 1946-1949, 1950-1952 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Health Services, 1943-1951 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Health Services, 1943-1951 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Institute of Andean Biology, Lima - High Altitude Studies - (Hurtado, Alberto), 1934-1942 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Institute of Andean Biology, Lima - High Altitude Studies - (Hurtado, Alberto), 1934-1942 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Institute of Andean Biology, Lima - High Altitude Studies - (Hurtado, Alberto), 1934-1942 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Institute of Andean Biology, Lima - High Altitude Studies - (Hurtado, Alberto), 1934-1942 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Institute of Andean Biology, Lima - High Altitude Studies - (Hurtado, Alberto), 1943-1952, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Institute of Andean Biology, Lima - High Altitude Studies - (Hurtado, Alberto), 1943-1952, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Institute of Andean Biology, Lima - High Altitude Studies - (Hurtado, Alberto), 1943-1952, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Institute of Andean Biology, Lima - High Altitude Studies - (Hurtado, Alberto), 1943-1952, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Institute of Andean Biology, Lima - High Altitude Studies - (Hurtado, Alberto), 1943-1952, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Institute of Andean Biology, Lima - High Altitude Studies - (Hurtado, Alberto), 1943-1952, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Institute of Andean Biology, Lima - High Altitude Studies - (Hurtado, Alberto), 1943-1952, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Institute of Andean Biology, Lima - High Altitude Studies - (Hurtado, Alberto; Travel Grant), 1952-1953, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Institute of Andean Biology, Lima - Nutrition - Equipment - (Picon, Emilio), 1952-1954 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Peru - Medical Sciences, 331.A
    - (Medical Sciences), 1919-1920, 1925-1926 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - LAM-1 Lambert, Robert A. "Medical Education in Peru", 1926 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - University of San Marcos, Lima - Bernales, Sergio E. - (Travel Grant), 1946-1948, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 20)